League of Women Voters of Saratoga County; Records apap339
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
League of Women Voters of Saratoga County Records
1965-2016
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
apap339
5.59 cubic ft.
Founded in 1920, the League of Women Voters is a nonpartisan political organization that informs citizens about government, encourages their participation, and seeks to influence public policy through education and advocacy. One of nearly 60 local leagues in New York State, the League of Women Voters of Saratoga County (formerly the League of Women Voters, Saratoga Springs Area) formed in early 1965. This collection documents the operation and activities of this local league from its founding through 2010.
Access
Access to this record group is unrestricted.
Acquisition Information
Initial items in this collection were donated to the University Libraries, M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, by former longtime LWVSC president Barbara Thomas, July 15, 2013.
Barbara Thomas donated additional materials November 2, 2015 and November 10, 2016. The Saratoga Springs Public Library also donated materials on February 16, 2018.
Organizational Sketch
The (National) League of Women Voters (LWV) was founded by Carrie Chapman Catt in 1920 during the convention of the National American Woman Suffrage Association. The convention was held just six months before the 19th amendment to the U.S. Constitution was ratified, giving women the right to vote after a 72-year struggle.
The League began as a "mighty political experiment" designed to help 20 million women carry out their new responsibilities as voters. It encouraged them to use their new power to participate in shaping public policy. From the beginning, the League has been an activist, grassroots organization whose leaders believed that citizens should play a critical role in advocacy. The League is proud to be nonpartisan, neither supporting nor opposing candidates or political parties at any level of government, but always working on vital issues of concern to members and the public.
The League, now open to men and women, has 150,000 plus members, and supporters in the U.S., with Leagues in every state, Puerto Rico, Washington, D.C., the Virgin Islands and Hong Kong. Statewide in New York, there are nearly 60 local leagues with approximately 8000 members.
The Saratoga County Chapter was founded in 1965, as a "provisional league," under the name of League of Women Voters of the Saratoga Springs Area. At the time, with the exception of Saratoga Springs, most of Saratoga County consisted of small towns and farming areas, with some residents of the southern portion of the county having closer ties to the Schenectady County Chapter of the league. Thus it was decided to make Saratoga Springs the hub of this new chapter, specifically including the towns of Saratoga Springs, Wilton and Greenfield. To fulfill national requirements, a thorough study of the community was prepared early in 1965, and members were recruited to meet the 25 member minimum. The chapter was granted authority from the national organization in early 1965, and had its first organizational meeting on April 8, 1965. A membership total of 59 was reported at the April 28, 1965 board meeting. In April, 1967 the organization was granted "full league" status.
In 1999, with the demise of the Southern Saratoga County LWV (previously know as the Shenendehowa LWV), it was decided to apply for expansion to include the whole county in the organization. Permission was granted by the national LWV on February 17, 2000 for the name change to League of Women Voters of Saratoga County (LWVSC). Members of disbanded chapters were invited to join. (Records of the LWV of Southern Saratoga County are not included in the collection.)
Since 2000, the LWVSC has expanded its activities and membership to serve the whole county. The 2010-2011 membership list includes approximately 160 members.
The stated mission of the LWVSC, like its parent organization, is as follows: The League of Women Voters, a nonpartisan political organization, encourages informed and active participation in government, works to increase understanding of major public policy issues, and influences public policy through education and advocacy.
The information provided above was gleaned from the following sources:
LWV League of Women Voters: History.(2011). Retrieved from http://www.lwv.org/history
LWV League of Women Voters of Saratoga County: About Us. (2011). Retrieved from http://www.lwvsaratoga.org/about.htm
League of Women Voters of Saratoga County Records, 1965-2010. File: Organizational Meeting and Study, 1965-04-08
League of Women Voters of Saratoga County Records, 1965-2010.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains the records of the League of Women Voters of Saratoga County (LWVSC), from its founding in 1965 through 2010. It documents the organization's internal functioning and its public activities during that time. Included are the administrative documents of the chapter: by-laws and revisions, membership and officer lists, annual reports, annual meeting program information, some correspondence, budget and financial statements, monthly meeting minutes, and monthly member bulletins (newsletters). Information on the work of the chapter in education, outreach and advocacy projects is detailed by project, and includes meeting notes, studies, reports, surveys, photographs and news clippings. In addition to the newsletters, there are various other publications the league sponsored. Also included are a small number of videotapes, mainly of local "Meet the Candidate" events.
While records of the disbanded LWV of Southern Saratoga County are not included in the collection, the Project and Subject Files contain a few projects in which this group participated, and a Clifton Park-Halfmoon Community Study from 1971, apparently prepared for purposes of securing provisional league status for that organization.
The archivist retained file titles created by the League of Women Voters of Saratoga County.
Researchers also may wish to consult the League of Women Voters of Albany County Records (APAP-128), the League of Women Voters of Rensselaer County Records (APAP-103) and the League of Women Voters of Schenectady County Records (APAP-210) held by the Department of Special Collections and Archives.
Arrangement of the Collection
The collection is organized into four series. Series 1, 2 and 4 are arranged chronologically. Series 3 is arranged alphabetically.
Women; Social Activists and Public Advocates; Public Servants; Politics and Politicians; Education; Election law--New York (State); Elections--New York (State); Local government--New York (State); Political planning--New York (State); Voter registration--New York (State); Voting--New York (State); Women--New York (State)--Saratoga County--Societies and clubs; Women in nonprofit organizations--New York (State)--Saratoga County; Women political activists--New York (State)--Saratoga County; Administrative records; Annual reports; Clippings; Correspondence; Financial Records; Minutes; Membership; Newsletters; Photographs; Programs (documents); Studies; Videotapes; League of Women Voters (U.S.); League of Women Voters of New York State; League of Women Voters of Saratoga County (Saratoga County, N.Y.)
- Administrative Files, 1965-2016; 1; 1.98 cubic ft.
  Arrangement
  Arranged chronologically.
  Scope and Contents
  The Administrative Files series consists of organizational records which document the activities of the Board of Directors. These include founding documents, by-laws and changes, annual reports to the national organization, monthly meeting minutes, and event programs from annual chapter meetings. Budgets, treasurer reports and event calendars are mainly interfiled with meeting minutes, as is some correspondence. There are gaps in some months and years. Files labeled "Other" contain a mixture of items, including correspondence, budgets, pamphlets, Voters Guides, annual program calendar flyers and study reports.
  - Bylaws, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Minutes, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Organizational Meeting and Study, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Budgets, 1965-1989 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Membership Lists, 1965-1991 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Minutes, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Fund Drive Letters, 1966-1968; 1970-1971; Undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Observer Corps, 1966-1968; 1980; Undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Committee Lists, 1966; 1981; 1987-1988 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Bylaws, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Minutes, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Minutes, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Other, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Finance Drives, 1968-1979; 1981-1990 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Minutes, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - 1969-1970 Annual Report, ca. 1969 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Other, 1969; Undated (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Board Lists, 1969-1971; 1981-1983; 1985-1989 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - 1970-1971 Annual Report (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Minutes, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Other, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Correspondence, 1970-1975 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Membership Lists, 1970-1971; 1973-1975 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Minutes, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - 1971-1972 Annual Report, ca. 1971 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Bylaw Changes, 1971; 1973 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Minutes, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - 1972-1973 Annual Report (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Minutes, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - 1973-1974 Annual Report, ca. 1973 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Minutes, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - 1974-1975 Annual Report, ca. 1974 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Minutes, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Minutes, 1976; Undated (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Membership Lists, 1976-1980 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Correspondence, 1976; 1980; 1982; 1985-1987; 1989 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Minutes, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Treasurer's Report, 1977-1984 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Minutes, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Minutes, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Annual Meeting Booklets, 1979-1981; 1984-1987; 1989; 1991-1995 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Minutes, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Other, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Minutes, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Membership Lists, 1981-1985 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Minutes, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Minutes, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Other, 1983; Undated (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Minutes, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Minutes, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Minutes, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Membership Lists, 1986-1990 (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Bylaws and Revisions, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Minutes, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Correspondence, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - Minutes, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - Bylaws Revised, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - Minutes, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - Correspondence, 1989; Undated (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - Financial Reports, 1988-1990 (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - Minutes, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - Correspondence, 1990; Undated (Box 1, Folder 62)
  - Minutes, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Membership Lists, 1991-1995 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Bylaws, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Minutes, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Minutes, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Minutes, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, 1994; Undated (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Minutes, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Minutes, 1996; Undated (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Membership Lists, 1996-1999 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Minutes, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Annual Meeting Booklets, 1997-2000 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Minutes, 1998; Undated (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Minutes, 1999; Undated (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Name Change to LWV of Saratoga County, 1999-2000; Undated (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Bylaws, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Minutes, 2000 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Membership Lists, 2000; 2002-2005 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Minutes, 2001 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Annual Meeting Booklets, 2001-2005 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Minutes, 2002 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Minutes, 2003; Undated (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Minutes, 2004; Undated (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Minutes, 2005 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Tax Status, 2005 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Minutes, 2006 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Annual Meeting Booklets, 2006-2010 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Membership Lists, 2006-2010 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Bylaws, 2007 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Minutes, 2007 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Minutes, 2008; Undated (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Minutes, 2009; Undated (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Minutes, 2010 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Annual Meeting, 2010 (Cd 1)
  - Annual Meeting Booklets, 2011-2015 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Annual Meeting, 2013 (Dvd 1)
  - Annual Meeting, 2014 (Dvd 2)
  - Annual Meeting, 2016 (Cd 2)
- Publications, 1965-2015; 2; 1.0 cubic ft.
  This series consists mainly of the monthly bulletins that were sent to LWVSC members and select members of the public. Each one contains a message from the President, information about chapter events, as well as state and national LWV news and conventions. They also inform members of meetings, candidate events, studies and advocacy projects and voter registration information. There are some missing months. Other publications in this series are Community Guides, Voters Guides and various booklets and pamphlets.
  - Bulletins, 1965 (Box 1 (2-Publications), Folder 1)
  - Bulletins, 1966 (Box 1 (2-Publications), Folder 2)
  - A Citizen's Guide to Saratoga Springs, 1967 (Box 1 (2-Publications), Folder 3)
  - Bulletins, 1967 (Box 1 (2-Publications), Folder 4)
  - Voter's Guides, 1967-1968 (Box 1 (2-Publications), Folder 5)
  - Bulletins, 1968 (Box 1 (2-Publications), Folder 6)
  - Bulletins, 1969 (Box 1 (2-Publications), Folder 7)
  - Bulletins, 1970 (Box 1 (2-Publications), Folder 8)
  - Miscellaneous, 1970; 1980-1985; 1987; 1994; Undated (Box 1 (2-Publications), Folder 9)
  - Voter's Guides, 1970; 1974 (Box 1 (2-Publications), Folder 10)
  - Bulletins, 1971 (Box 1 (2-Publications), Folder 11)
  - Bulletins, 1972 (Box 1 (2-Publications), Folder 12)
  - Bulletins, 1973 (Box 1 (2-Publications), Folder 13)
  - Bulletins, 1974 (Box 1 (2-Publications), Folder 14)
  - Bulletins, 1975 (Box 1 (2-Publications), Folder 15)
  - Voter's Guides, 1975 (Box 1 (2-Publications), Folder 16)
  - Bulletins, 1976 (Box 1 (2-Publications), Folder 17)
  - Voter's Guides, 1976-1978 (Box 1 (2-Publications), Folder 18)
  - Bulletins, 1977 (Box 1 (2-Publications), Folder 19)
  - Bulletins, 1978 (Box 1 (2-Publications), Folder 20)
  - Bulletins, 1979 (Box 1 (2-Publications), Folder 21)
  - Bulletins, 1980 (Box 1 (2-Publications), Folder 22)
  - Community Guides, 1980; Undated (Box 1 (2-Publications), Folder 23)
  - Voter's Guides, 1980; 1983 (Box 1 (2-Publications), Folder 24)
  - Bulletins, 1981 (Box 1 (2-Publications), Folder 25)
  - Study of Saratoga Springs School District, 1981; 1983-1984 (Box 1 (2-Publications), Folder 26)
  - Bulletins, 1982 (Box 1 (2-Publications), Folder 27)
  - Bulletins, 1983 (Box 2 (2-Publications), Folder 1)
  - Bulletins, 1984 (Box 2 (2-Publications), Folder 2)
  - In League with Eleanor by Hilda Watrous, 1984 (Box 2 (2-Publications), Folder 3)
  - Bulletins, 1985 (Box 2 (2-Publications), Folder 4)
  - Bulletins, 1986 (Box 2 (2-Publications), Folder 5)
  - Bulletins, 1987 (Box 2 (2-Publications), Folder 6)
  - Bulletins, 1988 (Box 2 (2-Publications), Folder 7)
  - Bulletins, 1989 (Box 2 (2-Publications), Folder 8)
  - Bulletins, 1990 (Box 2 (2-Publications), Folder 9)
  - Bulletins, 1991 (Box 2 (2-Publications), Folder 10)
  - Bulletins, 1992 (Box 2 (2-Publications), Folder 11)
  - Bulletins, 1993 (Box 2 (2-Publications), Folder 12)
  - Bulletins, 1994 (Box 2 (2-Publications), Folder 13)
  - Bulletins, 1995 (Box 2 (2-Publications), Folder 14)
  - Bulletins, 1996 (Box 2 (2-Publications), Folder 15)
  - Bulletins, 1997 (Box 2 (2-Publications), Folder 16)
  - Bulletins, 1998 (Box 2 (2-Publications), Folder 17)
  - Bulletins, 1999 (Box 2 (2-Publications), Folder 18)
  - Bulletins, 2000 (Box 2 (2-Publications), Folder 19)
  - Bulletins, 2001 (Box 2 (2-Publications), Folder 20)
  - Bulletins, 2002 (Box 2 (2-Publications), Folder 21)
  - Bulletins, 2003 (Box 2 (2-Publications), Folder 22)
  - Bulletins, 2004 (Box 2 (2-Publications), Folder 23)
  - Bulletins, 2005 (Box 2 (2-Publications), Folder 24)
  - Bulletins, 2006 (Box 3 (2-Publications), Folder 1)
  - Bulletins, 2007 (Box 3 (2-Publications), Folder 2)
  - Bulletins, 2008 (Box 3 (2-Publications), Folder 3)
  - Bulletins, 2009 (Box 3 (2-Publications), Folder 4)
  - Bulletins, 2010 (Box 3 (2-Publications), Folder 5)
  - Bulletins, 2011 (Box 3 (2-Publications), Folder 6)
  - Bulletins, 2012 (Box 3 (2-Publications), Folder 7)
  - Bulletins, 2013 (Box 3 (2-Publications), Folder 8)
  - Bulletins, 2014 (Box 3 (2-Publications), Folder 9)
  - Bulletins, 2015 (Box 3 (2-Publications), Folder 10)
- Project and Subject Files, 1968-2015; 3; 1.92 cubic ft.
  Arranged alphabetically.
  This series contains the records of major projects undertaken by the League, starting with Saratoga Springs City Charter Activities to the Famous Person Fundraisers. Other significant topics include: Emergency Services Study, Elder Services Program, Polling Place Accessibility Studies, Russian Delegation visits, and Student Voting Rights. These project files contain program descriptions, grant applications, studies, surveys, reports, news clippings, and photographs (unlabeled). Also included in this series are videotapes, DVDs, and CDs documenting chapter events.
  - 75th Anniversary of LWVNY, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - 75th Anniversary of LWVUS - Special Cancellation, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - 75th Anniversary of LWVUS - "The Stone that Started the Ripple", 1995; Undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - 1928 Press Release for Kathryn Starbuck and LWVNY, Undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Alternatives to Incarceration Consensus, 1992; Undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Balancing Justice Project, 1999-2000 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Barb Shots, 2010 (Cd 3)
  - Battlefield Event, 2015 (Dvd 3)
  - Candidate Events, 1970-1986; 1989 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Christmas Party, 2015 (Cd 4)
  - Clifton Park Community Study, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Constitution Day, 2008 (Video-tape 1)
  - Constitution Day - Grant Application, 2008 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Constitution Day - Evaluation Forms, 2008 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Constitution Day - Program Planning and Publicity, 2008 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Constitution Day - Report, 2008 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Daycare Survey and Report, 1969; Undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Day Care, 1985-1991 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Death Penalty - David Kaczynski, Presenter, 2005 January 27 (Video-tape 2)
  - Drug Law Reform, 2001 June 14 (Video-tape 3)
  - Emergency Services Study - Background, 1999-2000 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Emergency Services Study - Consensus and Position, 2000; Undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Emergency Services Study - Meetings, 1998-1999; Undated (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Emergency Services Study - Meeting and Study Materials, 1996-1997; Undated (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Emergency Services Study - Questionnaires, 1999-2000 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Emergency Services Study - News Clippings, 1998-1999 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Emergency Services Study - Numbering Procedures for 911 Service, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Expanded In-Home Services for the Elderly Program (EISEP) - Advocacy Materials, 1989-1990 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Expanded In-Home Services for the Elderly Program (EISEP) - Correspondence, 1989-1990; Undated (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Expanded In-Home Services for the Elderly Program (EISEP) - Articles and Notes, 1988; 1990-1991; Undated (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Expanded In-Home Services for the Elderly Program (EISEP) - Description of Programs, Undated (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Expanded In-Home Services for the Elderly Program (EISEP) - Letters of Support, 1990; Undated (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Expanded In-Home Services for the Elderly Program (EISEP) - Need Report, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Expanded In-Home Services for the Elderly Program (EISEP) - Newsclippings, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Expanded In-Home Services for the Elderly Program (EISEP) - Personnel and Advocate Lists, 1990; Undated (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Economic Opportunity Council (EOC) Elections Part 1, 1968; 1973; Undated (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Economic Opportunity Council (EOC) Elections Part 2, 1981-1982; Undated (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Famous Person Celebration - Elizabeth Cady Stanton, 2010 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Famous Person Fundraiser - Abraham Lincoln, 2009-2010; Undated (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Famous Person Fundraiser - Abraham Lincoln - Lincoln Coin Sets, 2010 (Oversized 1)
  - Famous Person Fundraiser - Abraham Lincoln - Photos, 2010 (Dvd 4)
  - Famous Person Fundraiser - Eleanor Roosevelt, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Famous Person Fundraiser - Susan B. Anthony, 2009 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Famous Person Fundraiser - Susan B. Anthony - "Only the Message Mattered", 2009 (Cd 5)
  - Focus on the Poor - Saratoga County Publication, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Focus on the Poor - Study Materials and Correspondence, 1972-1974 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Forum on Federal Budget Cuts, 1981; 1989 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Groundwater Protection Grant - Application and Press Release, 1981-1982; Undated (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Groundwater Protection Grant - Grant Award and Reports, 1981-1982 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Groundwater Protection Grant - Public Education Newsclippings, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Ice Cream Social, 2008 (Cd 6)
  - Ice Cream Social, 2014 (Dvd 5)
  - Ice Cream Social, 2015 (Dvd 6)
  - Information & Referral Study and Grant - Background and Consensus, 1988-1989 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Information & Referral Study and Grant - Provider Proposal and Timetable, 1989; Undated (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Information & Referral Study and Grant - Report to Founder (Gannett), 1989 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Information & Referral Study and Grant - Results, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Information & Referral Study and Grant - RFP, 1989; Undated (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Information & Referral Study and Grant - Survey, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Information & Referral Study and Grant - Survey and Meetings, 1989; Undated (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - League Annual Fundraiser, 2013 (Cd 7)
  - Letters (Advocacy), 1967-1969; 1973-1974; 1976; 1981-1988 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Library Funding Study, 1990; 1995-1997; Undated (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Media Center Committee - Background, 2003-2004; Undated (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Media Center Committee - Cable TV and Public Access, 1999; 2002; 2005; Undated (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Media Center Committee - Public Outreach, 2004-2005; Undated (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Meet the Candidates, 2001 October 29 (Video-tape 4)
  - Meet the Candidates, 2003 May 28 (Video-tape 5)
  - Meet the Candidates - Clifton Park, 2002 October 31 (Video-tape 6)
  - Meet the Candidates - Clifton Park, 2004 October 18 (Video-tape 7)
  - Meet the Candidates - Clifton Park/Halfmoon, Undated (Video-tape 8)
  - Meet the Candidates - Saratoga County Supervisors, Undated (Video-tape 9)
  - Meet the Candidates - Saratoga Springs Area, 2004 October 19 (Video-tape 10)
  - Meet the Candidates - Saratoga Springs Area - Complete Version, 2004 October 19 (Video-tape 11)
  - Meet the Candidates - Saratoga Springs Area, Undated (Video-tape 12)
  - Milk Cartons to Encourage Voting, Undated (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Mother Jones, 2012 (Cd 8)
  - Nonpartisan Political Policy, 1991; 1994-1998 (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - Nuclear Arms Forum, 1982; Undated (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - Polling Place Accessibility, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - Polling Place Accessibility - ADA Act and Checklist, 2001; 2004 (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - Polling Place Accessibility Survey - Ballston, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - Polling Place Accessibility Survey - Blank Form and Press Release, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 60)